International Programs, Campus Coordinator Records 1971-1984
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
International Programs, Campus Coordinator Records
1971-1984
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 197
10 linear feet 35 containers
Records related to WSU International projects in Jordan, Syria, Morocco, Mail, and other countries.
Organizational History:
International projects concerned with economic, agricultural, social and educational development began at Washington State University in 1952 with a Pakistan Project that was to run for almost 20 years. The Office of International Programs in the College of Arts and Sciences provided the management for that project and succeeding projects until 1978. The College of Agriculture was heavily involved in the projects and provided increasing assistance. A Campus Coordinator for international projects was established in the College of Agriculture for the University of Jordan Project (1975-1979). The Coordinator's office also acted as a clearing house for other projects in which the University was involved in the middle 1970's, such as those in Syria, Morocco, and Mali. In 1978 the International Program Development Office was established in the Graduate School of WSU to direct the international development projects. At that time the University was involved in several projects, with major efforts in Indonesia, Lesotho, and a cooperative project in Sudan.
By the mid-1980s, three offices--with similar names--were the focus of international programs at the university. The Office of International Programs in the College of Arts and Sciences was concerned with international students and faculty. (This office was subsequently renamed as the International Education Office.) The International Program Development Office in the Graduate School was concerned with development work, while. the International Project Support Office in the College of Agriculture was involved in the administration of projects.
Within the records of these projects some terminological confusion occasionally arises out of the similarity of names of the offices. In addition, there are many references in these records to international development as a subject concerning development in general.
The records reflect the role of the Office of the Director of Resident Instruction in international development programs of the College of Agriculture. One sequence is chiefly composed of material about a variety of projects and international subjects from the Office of the Director. Dr. Rodney Bertramson held this position from 1967 to 1979 followed by Dr. C. Alan Pettibone from 1979 to 1985. Dr. Pettibone was a member of the advisory committee for the International Program Development Office and a member of the Advisory Committee for the Indonesia Project.
A second and large sequence of record, it constituting the bulk of the material, is related to the Office of the Assistant to the Director of Resident Instruction, Dr. Martin V. Waananen. Dr. Waananen served as the Campus Coordinator for the University of Jordan project and the Indonesia Project. He also directed a training program which WSU carried out for the Peace Corps and the subsequent recruitment programs for Peace Corps/Action.
The record are arranged as two series. Series I consists of four boxes related to the role of the Director's Office. This series contains general information about a variety of programs, their work as a member of the advisory committee, including correspondence, final reports and project papers, participant training and budget information. It also contains information about the trip Dr. Pettibone took to Indonesia as a member of the Advisory Committee.
Series Two consists of 31 boxes of records for the Office of the Assistant to the Director. The records are arranged in alphabetical order incorporating the various projects and related material in international development. Twelve boxes on the University of Jordan project form a subseries at the end of the arrangement. The records include contract material: proposals, request for proposals, cost proposals, and in some cases the contract itself. There are also budget materials, including purchase orders and statements, quarterly and final reports.
The Collection is open for research use.
Records of the Washington State University College of Agriculture and Home Economics concerned with international programs were transferred to the Washington State University Libraries in 1985 (accession number UA85-13).
Washington State University --Office of International Programs--Records and correspondence.
Foreign study--Research--Archival resources
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; International Relations
- Director of Resident Instruction, 1
  - Consortium for International Development, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - International Agricultural Programs, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - International Development Programs, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International Development Programs, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - International Development Programs/ USAID/ Title 12, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - International Program Development Office, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - International Program Development Office; Advisory Committee, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - International Program Development Office; Strengthening Grant, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chile, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - China, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Iran; Training Program, Memorandum, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Korea; Memorandum, Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lesotho; Memorandum, Site Visit, Project Paper, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Libya, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mali, Morocco; Final Report, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - University of Jordan; Contract, Proposal, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - University of Jordan; Correspondence, Request for Proposal, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - University of Jordan; Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - University of Jordan; Final Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Indonesia
    - Advisory Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, Request for Expression of Interest, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, Memorandum, Personnel, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, Memorandum, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, Memorandum, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, Report on Women on the Project, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Final Report, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Memorandum, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Memorandum, March-June 1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Memorandum, September-December 1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Memorandum, Correspondence, January-May 1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Memorandum, Correspondence, June-July 1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Memorandum, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Participant Training, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Participant Training, January-April 1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Participant Training, Memorandum, Budgets, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Participant Training, Re-entry Material (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Project Paper, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Project Reports, Memorandum, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Project Reports, Memorandum, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Proposal, Project Continuation, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Proposal Continuation, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Reports, Amendment to Contract, Sept.-Dec. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Semi-Annual Report, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Trip, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Assistant to the Director of Resident Instruction (Campus Coordinator), 2
  - AID-OSU Weed Control Plan, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Africa; General Information, Operation Crossroads, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - China, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Consortium for International Development, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Egypt; Agricultural Mechanization, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Egypt; Major Cereals, Contract: Request for Proposal, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Egypt; Major Cereals, Contract: Technical Report, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Egypt; Major Cereals, Contract: Worksheets, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Hawaii; Farming Systems Project, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Hawaii; Farming Systems Workshop, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Hawaii and Indonesia Trip, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Indonesia; Agricultural Research Specialist: Correspondence and Scope of Work, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Indonesia; Agricultural Research Specialist: Memorandum and Final Reports, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Indonesia
    - Eastern Island Agricultural Project: Contract and Cost Proposal, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Books and Library Materials, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence and Memorandum, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - News Clippings, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Maps and Brochures (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Preliminary Information, Site Visit, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Site Visit, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Site Visit, March 1978 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Translation Services, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Indonesia Graduate School Project, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Expression of Interest, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Proposal, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Request for Expression of Interest, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Office of International Programs, Participant Training, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - World Bank Project, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Project Proposal, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Proposal; Draft, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - WSU Team Visit, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - International Development: Project Director
    - Consortium for International Development, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Orientation Materials, Miscellaneous, 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Participant Training, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Retreat Materials, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - USAID/Design Guidelines, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - International Program Development; Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Iran Training Program; Correspondence, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Iran Training Program; Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - International Projects; Budget Statements, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Budget Statements, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    - Budget Statements; AID/Africa, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - Indonesia, 1979-1979 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Iran, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Iran; CID, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - University of Jordan, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 93)
    - University of Jordan, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - University of Jordan, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - University of Jordan, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Mali, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Morocco, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Morocco, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - Office Expenses, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Peace Corps, 1976-1978 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Peace Corps, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Purchase Orders, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Purchase Orders, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Saudi Arabia, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Jordan Valley Agricultural Services Project; Advisory Committee, Annual Review, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Jordan Valley Agricultural Services Project; Advisory Committee, Quarterly Report, Orientation Material, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Libya; Trip Report, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Libya; Trip Report, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Libya; Clippings, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Mali; Contract, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - Design team, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - Expense Vouchers, James Sieber (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Expense Vouchers, Robert Harwood (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Expense Vouchers, John Schwendiman (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Lesotho; Colorado Contract, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - Contract/Acceptance (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Contract, Cost Amendment, Project Review Paper, 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Cost Proposal, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - Cost Reimbursement, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - Proposal, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 121)
    - Proposal Worksheets, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - Request for Proposal, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 123)
    - Correspondence and Memorandum, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 124)
    - Design Team, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 125)
    - Design Team Report, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Design Team Report (Draft), 1977 (Box 12, Folder 127)
    - Expenditures, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 128)
    - Memorandum, On-Site Review, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - Memorandum, Personnel and Travel, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - Memorandum, Travel Regulations, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - Memorandum, Travel Regulations, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Memorandum, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Orientation, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - Personnel, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 135)
    - Project Paper, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 136)
    - Report, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 137)
    - Resource Material, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 138)
    - Trip by Campus Coordinator, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 139)
    - General Information on Africa, Guide Book on Lesotho, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Morocco; Dryland Farming, Project no. 60014
    - Contract: Amendment, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 141)
    - Contract: Proposal, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - Contract: Proposal, Working Papers, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Contract: Request for Proposal, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - Personnel, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Project Paper/USAID, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - Morocco; Forage/Seed Project, Project no. 60015
    - Budget Materials, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 147)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal (Box 14, Folder 148)
    - Contract: Cost Reimbursement, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 149)
    - Contract: Proposal, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 150)
    - Contract: Proposal, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - Contract: Worksheets, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 152)
    - Final Report, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 153)
    - Final Report, French Translation, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Final Report, French Translation, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 156)
  - Morocco; Agriculture Extension, Project no. 60028
    - Contract, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal, Revised, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal, Drafts and Notes, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 161)
    - Contract: Proposal, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Contract: Request for Technical Proposal, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - Expenditures, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - Expenditures, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 165)
    - Final Report, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 166)
    - In-Country Expenses, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - Memorandum, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Personnel File, Wayne Bath, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - Personnel File, Kenneth Morrison, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 170)
    - Personnel File, Robert Wesselman, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Morocco; World Bank Project, Contract, Request for Technical Proposal, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - Panama; Proposed AID Project, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 173)
  - Pakistan; Cooperative Graduate School Program, Project Review Paper, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Peace Corps-Action Programs; Travel, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - Peace Corps-Action Programs; Philippine Trip, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - Peace Corps-Action Programs; Philippine Trip, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Peace Corps; Budget Reports, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Peace Corps; Contract, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Peace Corps; Contract Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Peace Corps-Action; Contract, Budget Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Peace Corps-Action; Contract, Expense Vouchers, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - Peace Corps-Action; Contract, Expense Vouchers, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Peace Corps-Action; Correspondence and Memorandum, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - Peace Corps; General Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 185)
    - Handbook, Strategy Contracts, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 186)
    - Internship Proposal, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 187)
    - Monthly Report Forms, 1976-1981 (Box 17, Folder 188)
    - Northwest Office, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 189)
    - Personnel File, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 190)
    - Personnel File, Larry Tadlock, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 191)
    - Personnel, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 192)
  - Somalia; Agriculture Research/Extension Project Request for Expression of Interest, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - Sudan; Design Team Report, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - Sudan; Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - Syria; Forage/feed Project, General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 196)
    - Memorandum, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 197)
    - Proposal, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 198)
    - Proposal, Cost, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 199)
    - Final Report, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - Visitation, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - Visitation, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 202)
    - Visitation Report, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 203)
  - Syria; Agricultural Sector Assessment Project, Scope of Work, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 204)
    - Short Term Assignment, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 205)
    - Final Report, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Syria; Agricultural Research and Production, Expression of Interest, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 207)
    - General Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - Tanzania; Manpower Project, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 209)
  - Yemen; Advisory Committee, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 210)
    - Contract: Request for Expression of Interest, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 211)
    - Design Team Report, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 212)
    - Design Team Report, Part II, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 213)
    - Design Team Report, Part III, Appendices A and C, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 214)
    - Design Team Report, Part IV, V, Appendix E, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 215)
    - Design Team Report, Part VI, VII, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 216)
    - Individual Team Members Report, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 217)
    - Individual Team Members Report, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 218)
    - Project Information, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 219)
    - Project Paper, 1978-1980 (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - University of Jordan, Assistantships, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 221)
    - B.S. Degree (Box 20, Folder 222)
    - Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 223)
    - Budget, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 224)
    - Budget, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 225)
    - Budget, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 226)
    - Budget, Billings, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 227)
    - Budget, Billings, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 228)
    - Budget, Billings, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 229)
    - Budget, Contractor's Agreement, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 230)
    - Budget, Contractor's Agreement, 1975-1979 (Box 20, Folder 231)
    - Budget, Cost Survey, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 232)
    - Budget, Grant and Contract Certification, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 233)
    - Budget, International Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 234)
    - Budget, Journal Vouchers, 1977-1979 (Box 21, Folder 235)
    - Budget Materials, Amendment II, Nov.-Dec. 1976 (Box 21, Folder 236)
    - Budget Materials, Billings, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 237)
    - Budget Statements, 1977-1981 (Box 21, Folder 238)
    - Budget Statements, Contractor's Certificate, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 239)
    - Communications: Office of International Programs, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 240)
    - Communications: Telephone Calls with Chief of Party, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 241)
    - Communications: Telephone Calls with Chief of Party, 1978-1978 (Box 22, Folder 242)
    - Contract, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 243)
    - Contract: Budget Analysis, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 244)
    - Contract: Correspondence,1975 (Box 22, Folder 245)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 246)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal and Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 247)
    - Contract: Cost Proposal, Working Papers, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 248)
    - Contract: Part II, Employee Biographical Data, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 249)
    - Contract: Development of the Faculty of Agriculture, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 250)
    - Contract: Management Statements, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 251)
    - Contract: Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 252)
    - Contract: Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 253)
    - Contract: Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 254)
    - Contract: Project Paper, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 255)
    - Contract: Request for Expression of Interest, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 256)
    - Contract: Request for Proposal, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 257)
    - Contract: Technical Proposal, drafts, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 258)
    - Contract: Preliminary Proposal, Mar. 1975 (Box 24, Folder 259)
    - Contract: Site Visit, Dr. Kasim, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 260)
    - Contract Continuation, Amendment, 1976-1978 (Box 24, Folder 261)
      - Amendment I, II, 1976, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 262)
      - Amendment II, 1978, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 263)
      - Amendment IV, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 264)
      - Amendment II and Correspondence, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 265)
    - Contract Continuation, AID, 1978-1980 (Box 24, Folder 266)
    - Correspondence: Controller's Office, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 267)
    - Chief of Party, I. A. Dyer, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 268)
    - Chief of Party, I. A. Dyer, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 269)
    - John Hyslop/ USAID, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 270)
    - Office of International Programs, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 271)
    - Office of International Programs, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 272)
    - Mari-Liisa Matalka, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 273)
    - Purchasing Office, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 274)
    - Purchasing Office, 1977-1979 (Box 25, Folder 275)
    - Dr. Subhi Qasem, 1975-1979 (Box 25, Folder 276)
    - Chief of Party, C. Gardner Shaw, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 277)
    - Chief of Party, C. Gardner Shaw, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 278)
    - Chief of Party, C. Gardner Shaw, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 279)
    - Chief of Party, C. Gardner Shaw, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 280)
    - Jordan Summaries, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 281)
    - Participant Training, Cost Analysis, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 282)
    - Short Term, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 283)
    - Short Term, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 284)
    - Short Term, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 285)
    - Short Term, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 286)
    - Short Term, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 287)
    - Short Term, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 288)
    - Short Term, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 289)
    - Short Term, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 290)
    - Other Agency Sponsored, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 291)
    - Retirement and Insurance Office, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 292)
    - USAID Final Report, 1975-1980 (Box 26, Folder 293)
    - Evaluation Report, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 294)
    - General Correspondence, February 1977-March 1978 (Box 27, Folder 295)
    - General Correspondence, March 1978-March 1979 (Box 27, Folder 296)
    - General Correspondence, April 1979-June 1979 (Box 27, Folder 297)
    - USAID Strategy Statement, 1979-1980 (Box 27, Folder 298)
    - Jordanian Students, 1976-1978 (Box 27, Folder 299)
      - Mahmoud Ali Salem, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 300)
      - Abdalla Al-Musa, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 301)
      - Mazen Ak Kawi, 1976-1979 (Box 27, Folder 302)
      - Akram Baqqain, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 303)
      - Samir El-Habbab, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 304)
      - Wadi Lubbadeh, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 305)
      - Nasri Haddad, 1976-1978 (Box 27, Folder 306)